# Jorge Fioranelli

**Engineering Leadership** 

US Visa Holder (E3)



Technology senior leader with more than 20 years of experience in the industry. Focused on culture, scaling great teams, leadership mentorship and technical excellence. Strong in system scalability, cloud computing, distributed systems and functional programming.

## **Professional Experience**



# **Director of Engineering**Jet.com & Walmart Labs

Sep 2015 – Present New Jersey, USA



- Head of 5 high-performance engineering teams (40+ people) across 3 locations: New York, Dublin and Bangalore
- Strong culture of technical excellence, mentoring and high productivity
- Cloud, Continuous Delivery, Functional Programming, Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, CQRS and Event Sourcing



## **Lead Consultant**

#### Readify

Apr 2010 – Sep 2015 Sydney, Australia

- Leader of multiple consulting teams
- Microsoft Australia Engineer (Microsoft Software Development Center)
- Domain-Driven Design, Distributed Systems, Continuous Integration, Event Sourcing, Performance Analysis



## **Engineering Manager**

#### Lagash Systems

Feb 2006 – Mar 2010 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Head of 2 agile teams (15+ people)
- Architecture & Project Management
- Microsoft Argentina Consultant (Microsoft Consulting Services)
- Domain-Driven Design, Performance Analysis, Continuous Integration



### **Senior Software Developer**

## Accenture

Jan 2003 – Feb 2006 Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Hands-on Tech Lead of a small team (3 engineers)
- Architecture, Design Patterns and Performance Analysis



#### Software Developer AutoTrader

Feb 1999 – Jan 2003

Buenos Aires, Argentina

- Development of a classified ads web application
- Development of a magazine management system

### **Education**

#### Master of Business Administration

2019 | University of Illinois

#### **BS Computer Engineering**

2003 | UADE

#### **Skills**

Engineering Leadership
Engineering Management
Cloud Computing
Microservices
Distributed Systems
Functional Programming
Domain-Driven Design
Event-Driven Architecture

### **Courses & Certifications**

Predictive Analytics and Data Mining
Implementing Domain-Driven Design
Principles of Reactive Programming
Principles of Functional Programming
Story Value Mapping
Continuous Delivery
Command Query Responsibility Segregation
Event Sourcing
Advanced Distributed Systems Design
Professional Scrum Master
Certified Scrum Master
Value Stream Mapping
TDD Randori

## **Public Speaking Events**

2019 | openfsharp.org | SF, US

2018 | openfsharp.org | SF, US

2016 | skillsmatter.com | London, UK

2016 | composeconference.org | NY, US

2015 | yowconference.com | Perth, AU

2015 | anzcoders.com | Sydney, AU

2014 | dddmelbourne.com | Melbourne, AU

#### **Publications**

engineeringladders.com fsharpworkshop.com fsharpreactivepatterns.com